Daniel Vera

Jr. Full Stack Software Engineer ready to help your business grow.

I am a New Yorker who finds an elegant solution to any problem in his way. Implementing solutions that are simple to utilize, yet thoroughly thought out and tested. My experience gives me a unique perspective on the need to provide ready to use, turn-key solutions to whomever I work with. Solutions that are image enhancing and exiting to the end user.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, NYC — Software Engineering Apprenticeship

 June 20202 – Sept 2020 – Completed a 12-week / 500+ hour immersive course on full-stack web development using a variety of modern programming languages and technologies.

iManagement inc., — On-Site Trade-Show tech/QA

 2017 – 2018 – Our team implemented an ordering system using iPads for over 400 vendors to track inventory and interface with buyers.

ROOT NYC, NYC — Digital Capture Coordinator

 2012 – 2013 – Produced digital equipment for multiple locations and onsite photoshoots. Worked directly with each photographer to find solutions for their needs.

Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, NY — Digital Print Lab Manager

o 2007 – 2008 – Implemented a zero down-time color calibrated print lab that produced projects for a quarter of the student body.

Zagat Survey, NYC — Software Quality Assurance Analyst

 2000 – 2002 – Stress tested websites to identify bottlenecks and used SQL queries to validate results from web queries

CONTACT

(646) 456-5521

dannyvera@gmail.com

www.danielvera.dev

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-vera-65bbb07/

www.github.com/dannycvera

SKILLS

REACT

API's

PostgreSQL

Express

NodeJS

Rails

MongoDB

Bootstrap

Heroku

GitHub

LANGUAGES

JavaScript HTML/CSS

SQL

Ruby

English

EDUCATION

General Assembly, NYC — Software Engineering Immersive June 2020 – Sept 2020

PROJECTS

Apartment Fix — A full-stack web application to document apartment issues, such as leaking plumbing, broken sheetrock, etc. Allowing the users to create, update and delete comments in regard to a new issue they've created. Images or videos can be directly uploaded on either the users mobile or desktop. Technologies: JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Axios, Keroku.

Black Girls Code — A full–stack collaborative redesign working with multiple developers and UX designers. The original non–profit's site needed an update on usability along with a responsive layout which would allow for viewing on mobile as well as the desktop. We also implemented a screen for creating events, which also allowed the user to update them as well as delete. Technologies: JavaScript, React, MongoDB, Node.JS, Mongoose, Axios, Keroku.

Photo Co-Lab — A web app allowing for users to upload photos and edit the color, contrast, saturation, etc. on their mobile phone or desktop computer. Other users can view the same image and make view edits and save their own. Technologies: JavaScript, React, Axios, AirTable.

Game of Thrones Quotes — Is a game where a user must click on the character image, they believe authored the random quote on the screen. Two outside API's were utilized. One to obtain the random quote and another to cross reference the character info such as image URL, name, title, etc. as well as obtain random wrong answers to display. Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, Axios

Photography Website — Personal photography website. Written entirely with HTML, CSS, and pure JavaScript.